[
  {
    "question": "160. To avoid rollbacks when you start, you should:",
    "choices": [
      "Stop on a flat area.",
      "Engage the clutch very quickly.",
      "Partly engage the clutch before you take your right foot off the brake."
    ],
    "answer": "Partly engage the clutch before you take your right foot off the brake."
  },
  {
    "question": "161. What is the proper way to hold the steering wheel?",
    "choices": [
      "Firmly with both hands on opposite sides of the wheel.",
      "With your right hand on the wheel.",
      "Firmly with one hand at the top of the wheel and the other hand at the bottom of the wheel."
    ],
    "answer": "Firmly with both hands on opposite sides of the wheel."
  },
  {
    "question": "162. Why should you back towards the driver's side?",
    "choices": [
      "Backing toward the right side is dangerous.",
      "So you can see better.",
      "Both answers are correct."
    ],
    "answer": "Both answers are correct."
  },
  {
    "question": "163. When backing, why is it important to use a helper?",
    "choices": [
      "It makes people think you are a better driver.",
      "There are blind spots you can't see.",
      "It's more fun when you have help."
    ],
    "answer": "There are blind spots you can't see."
  },
  {
    "question": "164. What is the most important hand signal you and your backing helper should agree on?",
    "choices": ["Stop.", "Go.", "Slowly."],
    "answer": "Stop."
  },
  {
    "question": "165. What are two special occasions where you should downshift?",
    "choices": [
      "When starting off fast and speed shifting.",
      "Before starting down a hill and before entering a curve.",
      "Before starting up a hill and when going around a curve."
    ],
    "answer": "Before starting down a hill and before entering a curve."
  },
  {
    "question": "166. When should you downshift automatic transmissions?",
    "choices": ["When going down grades.", "When going up grades.", "When going around curves."],
    "answer": "When going down grades."
  },
  {
    "question": "167. Retarders keep you from skidding where the road is slippery.",
    "choices": ["True.", "False."],
    "answer": "False."
  },
  {
    "question": "168. What are two ways to know when to shift?",
    "choices": [
      "Use engine speed (rpm) and road signs.",
      "Use your watch and engine sounds.",
      "Use engine speed (rpm) and use road speed (mph)."
    ],
    "answer": "Use engine speed (rpm) and use road speed (mph)."
  },
  {
    "question": "169. How far ahead should you look?",
    "choices": ["5-10 seconds.", "12-15 seconds.", "15-30 seconds."],
    "answer": "12-15 seconds."
  },
  
    {
      "question": "170. What are the two main things to look for ahead?",
      "choices": [
        "Road signs and traffic.",
        "Police and weigh stations.",
        "Traffic and road conditions."
      ],
      "answer": "Traffic and road conditions."
    },
    {
      "question": "171. What is your most valuable way to see the sides and rear?",
      "choices": [
        "By looking out the window.",
        "Checking your mirrors regularly.",
        "Getting out and inspecting the areas."
      ],
      "answer": "Checking your mirrors regularly."
    },
    {
      "question": "172. What does 'communicating' in mean in safe driving?",
      "choices": [
        "Letting other drivers know you're there to help prevent crashes.",
        "Using hand signals.",
        "Driving brightly colored vehicles."
      ],
      "answer": "Letting other drivers know you're there to help prevent crashes."
    },
    {
      "question": "173. If you go twice as fast your stopping distance will increase by:",
      "choices": ["Two times.", "Three times.", "Four times."],
      "answer": "Four times."
    },
    {
      "question": "174. Empty trucks have the best braking.",
      "choices": ["True.", "False."],
      "answer": "False."
    },
    {
      "question": "175. What is hydroplaning?",
      "choices": [
        "Driving in the snow.",
        "When the tires lose their contact with the road.",
        "When you hit a pot hole."
      ],
      "answer": "When the tires lose their contact with the road."
    },
    {
      "question": "176. What is black ice?",
      "choices": [
        "Dirty snow.",
        "Rain and snow mixed.",
        "A thin layer of ice clear enough that you can see the road underneath it."
      ],
      "answer": "A thin layer of ice clear enough that you can see the road underneath it."
    },
    {
      "question": "177. If the vehicle in front of you is smaller than yours, it can probably:",
      "choices": [
        "Out-run you.",
        "Stop faster than you.",
        "Take turns faster than you."
      ],
      "answer": "Stop faster than you."
    },
    {
      "question": "178. If you are driving a 30 foot vehicle at 55 mph, how many seconds of following distance should you allow?",
      "choices": ["4 seconds.", "6 seconds.", "8 seconds."],
      "answer": "4 seconds."
    },
    {
      "question": "179. If you swing wide to the left before turning right another driver may try to pass you on your right.",
      "choices": ["True.", "False."],
      "answer": "True."
    },
    
      {
        "question": "180. You should use low beams whenever you can.",
        "choices": ["True.", "False."],
        "answer": "False."
      },
      {
        "question": "181. What should you do before driving if you are sleepy?",
        "choices": [
          "Drink some coffee.",
          "Take some caffeine pills.",
          "Get some sleep before you drive."
        ],
        "answer": "Get some sleep before you drive."
      },
      {
        "question": "182. What effects can wet brakes cause?",
        "choices": [
          "Brakes can be weak or grab.",
          "Brakes to work better.",
          "Your foot can get tired."
        ],
        "answer": "Brakes can be weak or grab."
      },
      {
        "question": "183. How can you avoid wet brake problems?",
        "choices": [
          "Speed up, shift to a higher gear.",
          "Slow down, shift to a low gear, gently put on the brakes.",
          "Apply the brakes harder and faster."
        ],
        "answer": "Slow down, shift to a low gear, gently put on the brakes."
      },
      {
        "question": "184. You should let air out of hot tires so the pressure goes back to normal.",
        "choices": ["True.", "False."],
        "answer": "False."
      },
      {
        "question": "185. You can safely remove the radiator cap as long as the engine isn't overheated.",
        "choices": ["True.", "False."],
        "answer": "False."
      },
      {
        "question": "186. What factors determine your selection of 'safe' speed when going down a long steep downgrade?",
        "choices": [
          "Size of vehicle, traffic conditions, curves in the road.",
          "Condition of the brakes, radio bulletins, and alertness of the driver.",
          "Total weight of the vehicle, length of the grade, steepness, road conditions, and weather."
        ],
        "answer": "Total weight of the vehicle, length of the grade, steepness, road conditions, and weather."
      },
      {
        "question": "187. Why should you be in the proper gear before starting down a hill?",
        "choices": [
          "Because gravity can cause the speed of your vehicle to increase.",
          "Because you don't want to shift going down a hill.",
          "Because the clutch works better up a hill."
        ],
        "answer": "Because gravity can cause the speed of your vehicle to increase."
      },
      {
        "question": "188. What is a hazard?",
        "choices": [
          "Any road condition or other road user that is a possible danger.",
          "A flashing amber light.",
          "A small animal."
        ],
        "answer": "Any road condition or other road user that is a possible danger."
      },
      {
        "question": "189. Why make emergency plans when you see a hazard?",
        "choices": [
          "To have something to do while driving.",
          "In order to protect yourself and others.",
          "To avoid getting a ticket."
        ],
        "answer": "In order to protect yourself and others."
      },
      {
        "question": "190. What are some advantages of going right instead of left around an obstacle?",
        "choices": [
          "You can avoid a head-on collision.",
          "Taking the shoulder may be best.",
          "Someone may be passing to the left.",
          "All of these answers are correct."
        ],
        "answer": "All of these answers are correct."
      },
        
        {
          "question": "191. Stopping isn't always the safest thing to do in an emergency.",
          "choices": ["True.", "False."],
          "answer": "True."
        },
        {
          "question": "192. What is an 'escape ramp'?",
          "choices": [
            "Ramps that are located a few miles from the top of a downgrade to help you stop.",
            "A quick way to get out of town.",
            "Ramps to get on and off an interstate highway fast."
          ],
          "answer": "Ramps that are located a few miles from the top of a downgrade to help you stop."
        },
        {
          "question": "193. What are some things to do at an accident scene to prevent another accident?",
          "choices": [
            "Try to get your vehicle to the side of the road.",
            "If you're stopping to help, park away from the accident.",
            "Put on your flashers and set out reflective triangles.",
            "All of these answers are correct."
          ],
          "answer": "All of these answers are correct."
        },
        {
          "question": "194. Name two causes of fires:",
          "choices": [
            "Under-inflated tires and duals that touch.",
            "Tight turns and gravel roads.",
            "Driver smoking and following too close."
          ],
          "answer": "Under-inflated tires and duals that touch."
        },
        {
          "question": "195. Which of these can cause the vehicle to skid?",
          "choices": [
            "Not enough weight on the front axle.",
            "Over acceleration.",
            "Turning too sharply.",
            "All of these answers are correct."
          ],
          "answer": "All of these answers are correct."
        },
        {
          "question": "196. You are driving a vehicle that could safely be driven at 55 mph on an open road; but traffic is now heavy, moving at 35 mph, although the speed limit is 55. The safest speed for your vehicle in this situation is most likely:",
          "choices": ["35 mph.", "40 mph.", "45 mph."],
          "answer": "35 mph."
        },
        {
          "question": "197. Every time you park your vehicle and shut the engine off you should:",
          "choices": [
            "Leave it in gear (if it has a manual transmission).",
            "Apply the parking brake.",
            "Turn the steering wheel as far to the left as you can."
          ],
          "answer": "Apply the parking brake."
        },
        {
          "question": "198. For an average commercial vehicle being driven at 55 mph on dry pavement it will take about _______ to bring the vehicle to a stop.",
          "choices": [
            "The length of a football field (300 feet).",
            "Half the length of a football field (150 feet).",
            "Twice the length of the vehicle."
          ],
          "answer": "The length of a football field (300 feet)."
        },
        {
          "question": "199. Which of these statements about certain types of cargo is true?",
          "choices": [
            "Oversize loads can be hauled without special permits during daylight hours.",
            "When liquids are hauled, the tank should always be loaded completely full.",
            "Unstable loads such as hanging meat or livestock require extra caution on curves."
          ],
          "answer": "Unstable loads such as hanging meat or livestock require extra caution on curves."
        },
        {
          "question": "200. Which of the following statements about backing is true?",
          "choices": [
            "Backing is always dangerous.",
            "You should back and turn towards the driver's side whenever possible.",
            "You should use a helper and communicate with hand signals.",
            "All of these are true."
          ],
          "answer": "All of these are true."
        },
          {
            "question": "201. The most common cause of serious vehicle skids is:",
            "choices": [
              "Driving too fast for road conditions.",
              "Poorly adjusted brakes.",
              "Over-inflated tires."
            ],
            "answer": "Driving too fast for road conditions."
          },
          {
            "question": "202. The parking brake should be tested while the vehicle is:",
            "choices": [
              "Moving slowly.",
              "Moving at highway speed.",
              "Moving forward slowly."
            ],
            "answer": "Moving forward slowly."
          },
          {
            "question": "203. A driver's trip log if required:",
            "choices": [
              "May be brought up to date once a week.",
              "May be written in pencil.",
              "Must be shown immediately when an officer requests it."
            ],
            "answer": "Must be shown immediately when an officer requests it."
          },
          {
            "question": "204. When should the pre-trip inspection report from the last driver be reviewed?",
            "choices": [
              "During your pre-trip inspection.",
              "Once per week.",
              "It doesn't have to be reviewed."
            ],
            "answer": "During your pre-trip inspection."
          },
          {
            "question": "205. If you are stopped at a rest area and found to have a BAC (Blood Alcohol Concentration) of .02 you will:",
            "choices": [
              "Be placed out of service for 24 hours.",
              "Be placed out of service for 48 hours.",
              "Be placed out of service for 72 hours."
            ],
            "answer": "Be placed out of service for 24 hours."
          },
          {
            "question": "206. How far ahead should you be looking while driving in town?",
            "choices": [
              "1 block.",
              "2 blocks.",
              "As far ahead as you can see."
            ],
            "answer": "1 block."
          },
          {
            "question": "207. How does 'bleeding tar' effect the road surface and driving conditions?",
            "choices": [
              "It is very sticky slowing down your vehicle.",
              "Tar in the road pavement rises to the road surface in very hot weather causing the roads to become very slippery.",
              "It does not affect the road surface or driving conditions."
            ],
            "answer": "Tar in the road pavement rises to the road surface in very hot weather causing the roads to become very slippery."
          },
          {
            "question": "208. Converter dollies built on or after March 1, 1998 are required to have anti-lock brakes. These dollies will have:",
            "choices": [
              "A yellow malfunction lamp in the center of the dolly.",
              "A yellow malfunction lamp on the left side of the dolly.",
              "A yellow malfunction lamp on the right side of the dolly."
            ],
            "answer": "A yellow malfunction lamp on the right side of the dolly."
          },
          {
            "question": "209. What is the minimum length for mud flaps?",
            "choices": [
              "Within 6 inches from the surface of the road.",
              "Within 8 inches of the surface of the road.",
              "Within 10 inches of the surface of the road."
            ],
            "answer": "Within 8 inches from the surface of the road."
          },
          {
            "question": "210. How long does it take a typical tractor trailer to clear a single track? A double track?",
            "choices": [
              "It takes 7 seconds to clear a single track, and more than 10 seconds to clear a double track.",
              "It takes 10 seconds to clear a single track, and more than 12 seconds to clear a double track.",
              "It takes 14 seconds to clear a single track, and more than 15 seconds to clear a double track."
            ],
            "answer": "It takes 14 seconds to clear a single track, and more than 15 seconds to clear a double track."
          },
          
            {
              "question": "211. What is the definition of 'sleep debt'?",
              "choices": [
                "The cumulative effect of not getting enough sleep.",
                "The money you owe hotels after resting there.",
                "The amount of sleep you get each day."
              ],
              "answer": "The cumulative effect of not getting enough sleep."
            },
            {
              "question": "212. Name some important steering system parts:",
              "choices": [
                "Tie rod, spindle, and pitman arm.",
                "Leaf spring, vehicle frame, and torque rod.",
                "Main spring, axle, and spring shackle."
              ],
              "answer": "Tie rod, spindle, and pitman arm."
            },
            {
              "question": "213. What is the minimum tread depth for front tires?",
              "choices": [
                "1/32 inch.",
                "2/32 inch.",
                "4/32 inch."
              ],
              "answer": "4/32 inch."
            },
            {
              "question": "214. When using your fire extinguisher you should get as close to the fire as possible.",
              "choices": [
                "True.",
                "False."
              ],
              "answer": "False."
            },
            {
              "question": "215. Name some things you should check on the FRONT of your vehicle during your pre-trip inspection:",
              "choices": [
                "Low beams, high beams, four-way flashers, and turn signals.",
                "Windshield wipers, mirrors, and hood latches.",
                "Oil, transmission, air compressor, and radiator."
              ],
              "answer": "Low beams, high beams, four-way flashers, and turn signals."
            },
            {
              "question": "216. Why are placards used?",
              "choices": [
                "So hazardous materials are not mixed with food.",
                "It is the law.",
                "To communicate the risk."
              ],
              "answer": "To communicate the risk."
            },
            {
              "question": "217. Name some suspension system defects:",
              "choices": [
                "Broken leaves in leaf spring and cracked or broken spring hanger.",
                "Leaking shock absorbers.",
                "All of the answers are correct."
              ],
              "answer": "All of the answers are correct."
            },
            {
              "question": "218. What is the minimum tread depth for tires other than front tires?",
              "choices": [
                "2/32 inch.",
                "3/32 inch.",
                "4/32 inch."
              ],
              "answer": "2/32 inch."
            },
            {
              "question": "219. How can you avoid the effects that wet brakes can cause?",
              "choices": [
                "Slow down and place the transmission in low gear.",
                "Gently put on the brakes and increase engine rpm, cross the water while keeping light pressure on the brakes.",
                "When out of water, maintain light pressure on the brakes for a short distance.",
                "All of these answers are correct."
              ],
              "answer": "All of these answers are correct."
            },
            {
              "question": "220. What things should you check during a trip?",
              "choices": [
                "Check load stability by slightly swerving left to right in your lane.",
                "Map, directions, and weather report.",
                "Watch gauges, mirrors, and use your senses to check for problems...LOOK, LISTEN, AND SMELL."
              ],
              "answer": "Watch gauges, mirrors, and use your senses to check for problems...LOOK, LISTEN, AND SMELL."
            },
            
              {
                "question": "221. Why should you be in the proper gear before starting down a hill?",
                "choices": [
                  "Because you need to be in the same gear at the bottom of the hill.",
                  "You will not be able to shift into a lower gear once you are going down a hill.",
                  "Because the clutch is made to be used on even surfaces."
                ],
                "answer": "You will not be able to shift into a lower gear once you are going down a hill."
              },
              {
                "question": "222. What is an advantage of going right instead of left around an obstacle?",
                "choices": [
                  "There is no advantage.",
                  "It is much easier to turn a truck to the right.",
                  "If you are blocked on both sides, a move to the right won't force anybody into opposing traffic lane and a possible head-on collision."
                ],
                "answer": "If you are blocked on both sides, a move to the right won't force anybody into opposing traffic lane and a possible head-on collision."
              },
              {
                "question": "223. Name two situations where legal maximum weights may not be safe to haul:",
                "choices": [
                  "During bad weather or in mountains.",
                  "Through tunnels and over bridges.",
                  "At night or during heavy traffic."
                ],
                "answer": "During bad weather or in mountains."
              },
              {
                "question": "224. What three things related to cargo are the driver's responsibility?",
                "choices": [
                  "Inspecting the cargo, recognizing overloads, and properly securing the cargo.",
                  "Inspecting the cargo, hauling the cargo, and securing the cargo.",
                  "Weighing the cargo, securing the cargo, and delivering the cargo."
                ],
                "answer": "Inspecting the cargo, recognizing overloads, and properly securing the cargo."
              },
              {
                "question": "225. What is a hazardous materials placard?",
                "choices": [
                  "Signs put on the outside of a vehicle which identify the hazard class of the cargo.",
                  "Signs put on the back of a vehicle which identify the hazard class of the cargo.",
                  "Signs put on the outside of a vehicle which identify the hazard class and weight of the vehicle."
                ],
                "answer": "Signs put on the outside of a vehicle which identify the hazard class of the cargo."
              },
              {
                "question": "226. What must you check before transporting a sealed load?",
                "choices": [
                  "That the seal is authentic.",
                  "That the load is properly secured.",
                  "That the placard numbers match the seal numbers."
                ],
                "answer": "That the load is properly secured."
              },
              {
                "question": "227. How do you calculate how many seconds of following distance space you have?",
                "choices": [
                  "Wait until the vehicle ahead of you passes a clear landmark, then count off the seconds until you reach the same spot.",
                  "Wait until the vehicle ahead of you passes a clear landmark, then count off the seconds until you reach the same spot, then multiply your figure by 2.",
                  "Divide your speed by four and add one second for every ten feet of trailer you are hauling."
                ],
                "answer": "Wait until the vehicle ahead of you passes a clear landmark, then count off the seconds until you reach the same spot."
              },
              {
                "question": "228. What is a 'pull-up'?",
                "choices": [
                  "When pulling off the shoulder you pull up until the trailer is straight.",
                  "A maneuver performed by a tow truck to pick up an overturned truck.",
                  "Pulling forward while backing a trailer to reposition it."
                ],
                "answer": "Pulling forward while backing a trailer to reposition it."
              },
              {
                "question": "229. What should wheel bearing seals be checked for?",
                "choices": [
                  "Leaks.",
                  "Gasoline.",
                  "Color changes."
                ],
                "answer": "Leaks."
              },
              {
                "question": "230. Select the proper collision procedures that are required for any collision that you are involved in; in which you are not seriously injured.",
                "choices": [
                  "Protect the area.",
                  "Notify the authorities.",
                  "Care for the injured.",
                  "All of these are required."
                ],
                "answer": "All of these are required."
              }
                        
                    
        ]        
      
      
